Tom Eagle BEng

81 Tarvin Road, Boughton, Chester, CH3 5EF 07941 939374 tomeagle79@gmail.com

Personal Profile

Mature Mechanical Engineering Graduate with 7 years proven capabilities in successfully managing own property services business and experience of consistently providing excellent customer service, delivering projects on time and on budget. Passionate about sustainability and renewable energy with a particular interest in wind and hydro power. Currently working for a sustainable building company while studying on an MSc course in renewable energy.

Possesses advanced problem-solving and fault finding skills, allied to sound practical judgement and has a track record of effectively working in the field. Has an affinity with IT and other technology and excellent numeracy and literacy, enabling effective and efficient record keeping and administration.

Qualifications

- Renewable Energy and the Built Environment MSc at the Centre for Alternative
 Technology, Machynlleth. Specialising in wind power. Having completed the
 commercial wind module in February, I have had experience of wind farm constraint
 mapping, using the WindFarmer software, and have gained valuable knowledge of
 feasibility studies, environment impact assessment and energy generation forecasting
- 1st class honours Mechanical Engineering UMIST (2000)
- A levels Maths (A), Physics (A), Gen Studies (A), Geography (C) 1997

Employment History

Project assistant EcoVert Solutions Oct 2012 to present

EcoVert provides solutions to problems such as damp period properties, often caused by unsympathetic use of modern materials. Natural materials like lime mortars, hemp, cork and wood-wool insulation are used in their place, that also have low embodied energy and a low carbon footprint. EcoVert also works with modern properties and offers retrofit and new build consultation and construction services, up to PassivHaus levels.

National Trust Environment Volunteer (Wales environment team) March 2012 - March 2013

In the role of environment volunteer, I worked with the EPA's (environmental practice advisers) in Wales. The projects that I was involved in were: assessing the NT's holiday properties for energy efficiency, and creating a solar and human-powered mobile generator for the trust to promote their environmental work.

Owner/Manager, Eagle Property Services – Chester April 2005 – October 2012

Responsible for managing and carrying out property maintenance/development contracts. These range from minor repairs and mechanical/electrical installations to full property refurbishment valued up to £55,000. Services provided include kitchen and bathroom renovation, plumbing and mechanical, electrical work, joinery.

Accomplishments

Eagle Property Services

- Set up own property maintenance company and managed contracts for property renovations valued up to £55,000, which has been running successfully for 8 years.
 Managed to maintain business through difficult period in the construction industry.
- Sourced, planned and coordinated groups of tradespeople to fully meet the project criteria.
- Learned and used MS FrontPage software to create a website to promote property company.
- Achieved certification under BS7671: requirements for electrical installations (16th edition).

Teaching/tutoring

- Coached several secondary school pupils to successful GCSE and A level results.
- Taught GCSE science to secondary school pupils as part of PGCE course.

University

- Achieved first class honours degree in Mechanical Engineering from one of UK's premier institutions.
- Award for outstanding results in fluid mechanics and thermodynamics at University (> 90% pass rate).
- Used word processing and spreadsheet software packages to produce many technical reports to a high standard.
- Learned programming language from scratch to develop material testing equipment for university dissertation.

Core competencies

- High level of numeracy, have achieved 95 percentile in competency tests.
- Tendering skills through providing quotes for customers of property business.
- IT skills: proficient user of MS office programs. Experience with WindFarmer, AutoCAD and programming languages (C and HTML). Able to learn and apply new software packages and technologies quickly and effectively.
- Problem solving and fault diagnosis on mechanical and electrical systems.
- Teaching and presentation skills.